# Joonwon Choi

Senior Formal Verification Engineer at Apple
One Apple Park Way, Cupertino, CA 95014
+1-339-225-5940 | joonwonc@alum.mit.edu | http://joonwon.net/c

## **Current Position**

#### Formal Verification Engineer, Apple

03/15/2021 - Current

I have worked on formally verifying memory subsystems and fabrics in Apple silicon. Reasoning about memory subsystems and fabrics is challenging due to the many optimizations involved in increasing system performance. Our team employs formal-methods tools to provide mathematical guarantees that the system is both safe and live.

# Education

### Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2016 - 02/17/2021

Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

#### Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2014 - 06/03/2016

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

#### **Seoul National University**

03/01/2006 - 02/26/2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Double major in Mathematical Sciences

- Graduated with honors (summa cum laude)

#### Selected Publications

- [1] Revamping the Formal Semantics of Verilog for Efficient, Modular, and Foundational Verification. *submitted*.
- [2] Hemiola: A DSL and Verification Tools to Guide Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols. Joonwon Choi, Adam Chlipala, Arvind.

**CAV'22** (regular paper, Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer-Aided Verification).

[3] **Structural Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols**. *Joonwon Choi* 

PhD Thesis in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.

[4] Integration Verification Across Software and Hardware for a Simple Embedded System.

Andres Erbsen, Samuel Gruetter, Joonwon Choi, Clark Wood, Adam Chlipala.

**PLDI'21** (Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation).

[5] EverCrypt: A Fast, Verified, Cross-Platform Cryptographic Provider.

Jonathan Protzenko, Bryan Parno, Aymeric Fromherz, Chris Hawblitzel, Marina Polubelova, Karthikeyan Bhargavan, Benjamin Beurdouche, *Joonwon Choi*, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Natalia Kulatova, Tahina Ramananandro, Aseem Rastogi, Nikhil Swamy, Christoph M. Wintersteiger, and Santiago Zanella-Bequelin.

**SP'20** (IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy).

[6] Crellvm: Verified Credible Compilation for LLVM.

Jeehoon Kang, Yoonseung Kim, Youngju Song, Juneyoung Lee, Sanghoon Park, Mark Dongyeon Shin,

Yonghyun Kim, Sungkeun Cho, *Joonwon Choi*, Chung-Kil Hur, and Kwangkeun Yi. **PLDI'18** (*Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation*).

[7] Kami: A Platform for High-Level Parametric Hardware Specification and its Modular Verification. Joonwon Choi, Muralidaran Vijayaraghavan, Benjamin Sherman, Adam Chlipala, Arvind. ICFP'17 (Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Functional Programming).

# Working Experience

**Presidential Science Scholarship** 

Apple, United States Formal Verification Engineer	03/15/2021 – Current
Microsoft Research Cambridge, United Kingdom Research Intern	07/02/2018 - 09/21/2018
allm Games, Korea Software Engineer (Skilled Industry Personnel as alternative military service)	04/13/2009 - 09/12/2011
<b>Google, Korea</b> Software Engineering Intern (SWE Intern)	01/05/2009 - 04/03/2009
Teaching Experience	
MIT 6.887: Formal Reasoning About Programs Teaching Assistant	Spring 2017
SNU 4190.310: Programming Languages Teaching Assistent	Fall 2013
Academic Services	
Program Committee: VSTTE 2024, PLDI 2024, CAV 2020 AE	
Honors & Awards	
Kwanjeong Educational Fellowship	Sep 2014 – May 2019
MIT Emerson Scholarship for Private Music Study	Sep 2014 – May 2018
<b>Top Honor (</b> <i>summa cum laude</i> <b>) Certification</b> Seoul National University	Feb 2013

Last updated: October 4, 2024

Mar 2006 - Feb 2013